Guide to the Stanford Historical Society Program Recordings SC0683
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Historical Society program recordings
1997-2014
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Historical Society
Miller, Carol
SC0683
1.75 Linear Feet
Audio and video tapes of annual meetings and public presentations on various topics in Stanford's history, including the museum, the Western CIV program, the human biology program, Herbert Hoover and Stanford, history of heart transplantation, overseas studies, KZSU (the student radio station), history of the endowment, and the Hoover Carillon. There are also some announcements of talks and handouts given at talks.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of the Stanford Historical Society, 2003, 2007, 2012 & 2015.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Audio and video tapes of annual meetings and public presentations on various topics in Stanford's history, including the museum, the Western CIV program, the human biology program, Herbert Hoover and Stanford, history of heart transplantation, overseas studies, KZSU (the student radio station), history of the endowment, and the Hoover Carillon. There are also some announcements of talks and handouts given at talks.
Stanford University -- General subdivision--History.;; Stanford Historical Society; Stanford Historical Society; Miller, Carol; Stanford Historical Society
- Recordings, 1997-2006; Accession ARCH-2003-213
  - Harry Sanders, Jr., "Early Campus Planning: 1956-1976", 1997 Jan 15; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Bob Rosenzweig, Annual Meeting - Governing the Modern University: Is it Even Worth Trying, 5/20/1997; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Don Winbigler, A Collection of Letters, 12/10/1997; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Art Barnes, Is There Life After the Stanford Band?, 1/13/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Bliss Carnochan, History of Humanities Center, 2/18/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Van Harvey, Religious Studies at Stanford: 1906-1998, 3/12/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Donald Kennedy, The Last of Your Springs, 10/12/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Lorenz Eitner, Mrs. Stanford's Great Museum: 1894-1998, 12/1/1998; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Stewart Gillmor, Stanford Sadie & The Early Years of KZSU Radio, 1/28/1999; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Ken Arrow, Paul Berg, Steve Chu, Panel Discussion Featuring Stanford Nobel Laureates, 11/4/1999; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Bob Hamrdla, T.J. Babbitt, Stanford Overseas Studies: A Vision Proved, 2/17/2000; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Marsh McCall, Annual Meeting - Continuing Studies Program: Stanford's Vision of Adult Education, 5/11/2000; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Paul Seaver, George Knoles, Western CIV Program at Stanford, 10/10/2000; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Elena Danielson, I Only Ring for Peace: The History of the Hoover Carillon at Stanford, 11/7/2000; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Bob Gregg, Robert Huw Morgan, The Inside Stories: Memorial Church and its Murray-Harris Organ, 1/16/2001; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - George Nash, Annual Meeting - Herbert Hoover and Stanford University, 4/26/2001; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Isaac Stein, SHS 25th Anniversary - Keynote Address: What is Past is Prologue, 5/8/2001; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Dornbush, Hastorf, & Kennedy, The History of the Program in Human Biology, 10/9/2001; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - James Risser, From Stanford to the Pulitzer: Success Stories of the Knight Fellows, 3/12/2002; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Jean Coblentz, Supporting Service to Stanford: Who, What, and Why are the Stanford Associates, 2/4/2003; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - John Pearson, The World Comes to the Farm: History of International Students, 3/4/2003; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Bob Augsburger, Annual Meeting - Evolution of An Endowment: 100 Years of Trusteeship, 5/13/2003; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Norman Shumway, History of Heart Transplantation, 2/13/1997; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - David Neuman, Current Planning … Planning Futures, 4/29/1997 (Box 1)
  - Bob Rosenzweig, Annual Meeting - Governing the Modern University: Is it Even Worth Trying?, 5/20/1997; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Bliss Carnochan, English at Stanford: 1891 – 2000, 2/20/2001; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Margaret O'Mara, Campus and City Plans: The Design and Influence of Stanford's Land Developments, 2004 Jan 22; 1 optical disc(s) (cd)
  - Chris Chafe, Margaret Kimball, The Renovated Knoll: Presidents, Precedents, and Computer Music, 9/29/2006; 1 audiocassette(s) (dat) (Box 1)
  - Henry Lowood, How Stanford Spawned Silicon Valley: An Historical Perspective, 10/4/2006; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - David M. Kennedy, Annual Meeting – Stanford and the West, 5/10/2006; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 1)
  - Event announcements (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Handouts for talks by Sanders; Eitner; Hamrdla.& Babbitt; Danielson; Carnochan (2/20/01); and Dornbush, Hastorf, & Kennedy (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Recordings, 2006-2007; Accession ARCH-2007-123
  - Jon A. Erickson, Ray M. Purpur, "Stanford Stadium: Lecture and Tour", 2006 Nov 6; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 2)
  - David P. Lenox, "A Snapshot in Time"... Stanford University Campus Planning, 2007 Jan 30; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 2)
  - Herb Fong, Stanford Grounds and Plants: 30 Years of Changes and Beyond, 2007 Mar 14; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 2)
  - Annual Meeting. Reflections: Stanford in the 1990s, President Gerhard Casper in conversation with Alan Acosta, 2007 May 2; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 2)
    Access to Collection
    Restricted during lifetime of Casper.
  - Event postcards, announcements (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Recordings, 1977-2011; Accession ARCH-2012-006
  - Escondido Cottage talk, 1977 May 3; 1.01; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Richard Lyman in Conversation with Nancy Packer, 2004 May 12; 1.02; 1 computer file(s) (mp4) 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM)
  - Bob Murphy, Seven Decades of Stanford Sports, 2004 Sep 29; 1.03; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Annual meeting, Don Kennedy and Robert Rosenzweig, 2005 May 11; 1.04; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
  - Laura Jones, The "New" Union, 2007 Sep 25; 1.05; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
  - Larry Wolff, The Legendary Wayne Vucinich: Growing Up in Yugoslavia, 2007 Oct 29; 1.06; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
  - Catherine Milton, Haas Center and the Tradition of Public Service at Stanford, 2008 Feb 26; 1.07; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
  - Laura Jones, Stanford University Gymnasium dig, 2008 Mar 12; 1.08; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
  - Stanford Historical Society annual meeting, 2008 May 13; 1.09; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Jeffrey R. Koseff, A Sustainable Stanford in a Sustainable World: Lecture and Tour, 2008 Oct 20; 1.10; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
  - John P. Alderete, The Mayfield Brewing Company and the History of Palo Alto, 2008 Nov 5; 1.11; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
  - Clayborne Carson, The King Legacy at Stanford, 2009 Jan 12; 1.12; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
  - Al Camarillo, Reflections on Latinos at Stanford Over Three Decades, 2009 Feb 17; 1.13; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
  - Stanford in Turmoil: President Emeritus Richard Lyman, 2009 Mar 12; 1.14; 1 computer file(s) (aif)
  - Annual Meeting: business meeting, 2009 May 21; 1.15; 1 videotape(s) (minidv)
  - Dean Philip A. Pizzo, One Hundred Years of Medicine, 2009 May 21; 1.16; 1 computer file(s) (mp4) 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV)
  - What Does the Board of Trustees Actually Do?, 2009 Oct 27; 1.17; 1 computer file(s) (wav) 1 computer files(s) (MP4)
  - Gay at Stanford: Past, Present and Future, 2009 Dec 3; 1.18; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
  - Betsy Fryberger: From the Stanford Museum to the Cantor Arts Center--A Curatorial Perspective, 2010 Jan 7; 1.19; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Charles Junkerman, From Greystone Quarry to Stone River, 2010 Feb 17; 1.20; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
  - Gordon Chang, As Old as the University Itself: The History of Asian Americans at Stanford University, 2010 Mar 10; 1.21; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
  - Lenny Siegel, Jeanne Friedman, Georgia Kelly, David Pugh, Time of Realization: The Roots of the Stanford Peace Movement in the 1960s and 1970s, 2010 Apr 1; 1.22; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - 34th Annual Meeting: Business Meeting, 2010 May 25; 1.23; 1 computer file(s) (wav)
  - Professor Robert l. Byer, The History of Lasers at Stanford, 2010 May 25; 1.24; 1 computer file(s) (wav) 1 computer file(s) (MP4)
  - David L. Freyberg, Watering the Farm: Stanford’s Water Systems Old and New, Near and Far, 2010 Oct 13; 1.25; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Winona Simms, C. Matthew Snipp and Denni Woodward, Native American Life at Stanford: A Panel Discussion, 2011 Nov 10; 1.26; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
  - Steve Zippestein, Rabbi Patricia Karlin‐Neumann and Joe Gettinger, Jewish Life at Stanford, 2011 Jan 13; 1.27; 1 computer file(s) (mp3)
- Recordings, 2011-2014; Accession ARCH-2015-105
  - When the World Changed: The Impact of WWII on Women at Stanford, 2011 May 17; 1.1; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)
  - Stanford Pioneering Women I: A Conversation with Women Hired between 1958 and 1975, 2014 Aug 22 (Box 1)
  - Stanford Pioneering Women I: A Conversation with Women Hired Between 1958 and 1975., 2014 Aug 22; 1.2; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 1)